这个过程的第一个阶段是光源;也就是说，是什么产生了落下的光
The first stage in the process is the illuminant; that is, what creates the light that falls
在最终反映到我们眼中的场景中。光到了哪里来了
on the scene that is ultimately reflected into our eyes. So where does the light come
从？那么有许多不同的光源;发射白炽灯
from? Well there are many, many different sources of light; incandescence’s is emitted
通过热物体，可以是钨灯泡的白热灯丝，也可以是太阳。
by hot objects, that could be the white hot filament of a tungsten light bulb or it could be the sun.
旧时尚阴极射线管-如电视和旧电脑显示器中所见-产生
Old fashion cathode ray tubes—as found in televisions and old computer monitors—generate
通过在磷光体上发射非常高能的电子来发光，这些是接受的化学物质
light by firing very energetic electrons at phosphors and these are chemicals that accept
高能电子并将其转换成光子或光。
that high energy electron and convert that into photons or light.
我们还有发光二极管，气体放电管和激光器。
We also have light emitting diodes, gas discharge tubes and lasers.
早在1672年，艾萨克·牛顿（IsaacNewton）就开发了他所谓的光谱理论
Way back in 1672, Isaac Newton developed what he called the spectral theory of light and
他做了一个非常着名的实验，光线通过一个覆盖的洞进入房间
he did a very famous experiment, light entered the room through a hole in a covering over
窗户进入棱镜，在那里他看到它分裂成许多不同的颜色。
the window and entered a prism where he saw that it was split into many different colors.
然后他能够证明他可以重新组合多种颜色的光
And then he was able to show that he could recombine the multiple colors of light back
成一束白光。你在这里看到的是艾萨克·牛顿的形象
into a single beam of white light. What you see here is an image of Isaac Newton’s
笔记本记录了他做过的这个实验。
notebook that records this experiment that he did.
一个非常标志性的图像是一束白光进入棱镜并被分裂成
A very iconic image is of a beam of white light entering a prism and being split into
彩虹的所有颜色。这些不同的颜色代表不同频率的光
all of the colors of the rainbow. These different colors represent light of different frequencies
我们倾向于根据它来描述特定颜色光的频率
and we tend to describe the frequency of a particular color of light in terms of its
波长。它是一个长度，以纳米为单位测量;十到九
wavelength. It is a length and it is measured in units of nanometers; ten to the minus nine
米。现在，并非所有的光都是可见的，人类能够在两者之间看到光
meters. Now, not all light is visible, human beings are able to see light between about
400纳米和700纳米。我们的光波长短于400纳米
400 nanometers and 700 nanometers. Light with wavelengths shorter than 400 nanometers we
我们称之为波长大于700纳米的紫外线和光线
refer to as ultra-violet and light with wavelengths greater than 700 nanometers we refer to as
红外线。光是电磁波，如果我们
infra-red. Light is an electromagnetic wave and if we
从图形上看，我们看到有两个
look at this graphically we see that there are two
自增强波，沿x轴在这个方向上穿过空间。之一
self-reinforcing waves, moving through space in this direction along the x axis. One of
那些波是一个电场;另一波是磁场。一个长度
those waves is an electric field; the other wave is a magnetic field. The length of a
这些波中的任何一个的单个周期我们称为波长并且非常普遍地给出
single cycle of either of these waves we refer to as the wavelength and very commonly give
它是符号lambda。所以波长是单个的长度
it the symbol lambda. So the wavelength is the length of a single
这种电磁波的周期和光的周期在400到700纳米之间。
cycle of this electromagnetic wave and for light it is between 400 and 700 nanometers.
我们现在考虑黑体散热器和两种最常见的黑体源
Let’s now consider black body radiators and the two most common black body sources
我们使用的光是传统的白炽钨灯泡，尽管现在这些
of light that we use are the traditional incandescent tungsten light bulb, though these are now
走出时尚，和太阳。太阳是天空中非常热的物体
going out of fashion, and the sun. The sun is a very hot object in the sky that emits
可见光。黑体散热器的光量
visible light. The amount of light that a black body radiator
这里，曲线给出了作为其波长函数的函数。可见光范围
emits as a function of its wavelength is given by this curve here. The visible range of light
在这里显示。该曲线由普朗克定律描述，并且包含大量数据
is shown here. This curve is described by Planck’s law and it contains a large number
const的，这个表达式中的一个术语是T，即温度
of constance, and one of the terms in this expression is T, that is the temperature of
黑体散热器。那是钨丝的温度或它是温度
the black body radiator. That is the temperature of the tungsten filament or it is the temperature
太阳表面。通常，这些数量级为数千
of the surface of the sun. Typically, these are in the order of thousands
开尔文度。曲线有一个非常清晰的峰值，以及这个峰值的波长
of degrees Kelvin. The curve has got a very clear peak, and the wavelength of this peak
由维恩位移定律给出，这表明波长是相关的
is given by the Wien displacement law, and what this shows is that the wavelength associated
该峰值的最大值与温度成反比。
with the maximum of this peak is inversely related to the temperature.
因此，低温具有与峰值相关的大λ并且随着温度升高
So low temperatures have a large lambda associated with the peak and as the temperature increases
这个lambda行动，减少。它移动到更短的波长。我们实际上有一个
this lambda acts, decreases. It moves to a shorter wavelength. And we actually have an
直观的感觉：我在这里绘制的是黑体发射曲线
intuitive feel for this: what I have plotted here are the black body emission curves for
在不同温度范围内的黑体-从1000开尔文到6000开尔文-和我们一样
black bodies at a range of different temperatures — from 1000 Kelvin up to 6000 Kelvin — and as we
可以看出，随着温度的升高，与最大值相关的波长是
can see, as the temperature increases, the wavelength associated with the maximum is
向更小的波长移动......它变得越来越蓝。所以它的温度
moving towards a smaller wavelength … it is becoming more blue. So as its temperature
增加，与最大发射相关的波长移动到更低的波长，
increases, the wavelength associated with the maximum emission moves to lower wavelengths,
更蓝的颜色。在我们的语言中，我们使用颜色来描述
to bluer colors. In our language we use colors to describe
温度。一些非常热的东西，即将开始的金属能够
temperatures. Something that is pretty hot, metal that is just about to begin be able
为了工作，我们描述为炽热。随着我们增加温度，它变成了
to be worked, we describe as being red hot. As we increase the temperature it becomes
黄色的热，它发出不同的颜色，它现在更黄色和温度
yellow hot, it is glowing a different color, it is more yellow now and as the temperature
上升它开始发出白光。我们称之为白热化。
goes up it starts to emit white light. And we refer to that as being white hot.
让我们来绘制其中一条黑体曲线。要开始，只需
Let’s have a go at plotting one of these black body curves. To get started with, just
为了让自己的生活更轻松，我将定义一个符号NM，代表
to make life a little bit easier for myself I am going to define a symbol NM, stands for
纳米并且等于十分之一到负九分。让生活更轻松一点。
nanometer and is equal to one by ten to the minus nine. Make life a little bit easier.
我将创建一个波长矢量。我打算把它叫做lambda，它就要开始了
And I am going to create a vector of wavelengths. I am going to call it lambda and it is going
从100纳米到10纳米不等，一直到千分之一
to vary from three hundred nanometers in steps of ten nanometers all the way up to a thousand
纳米，这是从近紫外线到光谱的红外线部分。
nanometers, this is going from the near ultra-violet through into the infra-red part of the spectrum.
现在我可以使用黑体功能计算黑体辐射器发射曲线。我通过
Now I can compute a black body radiator emission curve, using the black body function. I pass
在我感兴趣的波长范围内，我传递温度。我是
in the range of wavelengths that I am interested in and I pass in the temperature. And I am
要投入6500开尔文，这是太阳的温度。我可以绘制这条曲线，
going to put in 6500 Kelvin, which is the temperature of the sun. I can plot this curve,
一个轴将成为lambda而另一个轴将成为E.而这里我们有一个
one axis is going to be lambda and the other axis is going to be E. And here we have a
黑体辐射器的响应图。我要在那里放一个网格。
plot of the response of the black body radiator. I am going to put a grid on there.
让我们来看一下黑体散热器的情况，但色温较低
Let’s look at the case now for a black body radiator, but at a lower color temperature
我会稍微降低色温。
and I am going to reduce the color temperature a little bit.
所以让我们回到这里，我将把颜色减少500度。把它
So let’s come back here and I am going to reduce the color by 500 degrees. Put that
进入变量E.我将覆盖该情节，现在我将绘制E
into the variable E. I am going to overlay that plot and now I am going to plot E against
lambda和我将用dashline来做，所以我们可以看到有什么区别。和
lambda and I am going to do it with dashline so we can see what’s the difference. And
我们可以看到曲线较低;这个稍微凉爽的身体散发的更少
what we can see is that the curve is lower; this slightly cooler body is emitting less
整体能源。其遗漏的高峰已经从大约450纳米变为更接近
energy overall. The peak of its omission has moved from around 450 nanometers to closer
到480纳米。所以它有点凉爽，它的外观有点红。
to 480 nanometers. So it has got a little bit cooler and it is a little bit more red in its appearance.